Finding Aid for the Hemlock of Tennessee, Inc. Records
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Hemlock of Tennessee, Inc. Records Papers
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0205
6.67 linear_feet
- 13 VHS Videotapes
  - Last Rights - PBS (Box 1)
  - “Living Wills” - The Les Jamison Show (Box 1)
  - Right to Die - Saturday Night on Channel 4, August, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Derek Humphry and Betty Rollin - CBS News Nightwatch, October 29, 1986 (Box 1)
  - When the Time Comes - ABC Movie, March, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Dying With Dignity - Channel 5 KTLA, April 4, 1987 (Box 1)
  - “Headlines On Trial” - NBC, April 19, 1987 (Box 1)
  - “Let My Daughter Dies” - Frontline - PBS, March 23, 1988 (Box 1)
  - “Choosing Death” - NBC Nightly News, June, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Focus on You - NBC Nightly News, June, 1988 (Box 1)
  - A Time to Die - About Death With Dignity, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Alzheimer’s & Related Dementias, July 7, 1991 (Box 1)
- 21 Books
  - Baer, Louis Shattuck. Let the Patient Decide: A Doctor’s Advice to Older Persons (Box 1)
  - Brovins, Joan and Thomas Oehmke. Dr. Death: Dr. Jack Kevorkian’s RX Death (Box 1)
  - Hollingberry, Vilma. Is This the Day?: A Play (Box 1)
  - Humphry, Derek, ed. Compassionate Crimes, Broken Taboos: Mercy Killing (Box 1)
  - Humphry, Derek. Final Exit (Box 1)
  - Humphry, Derek. Lawful Exit (Box 1)
  - Humphry, Derek. Let Me Die Before 1 Wake: How Dying People End Their Suffering (1991) (Box 1)
  - Humphry, Derek. Let Me Die Before I Wake: Hemlock’s Book of Self-Deliverance for the Dying. 5th edition, 1987. (Box 1)
  - Humphry, Derek and Ann Wickett. Jean’s Wav: A Love Story (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Gretchen. Voluntary Euthanasia: A Comprehensive Biblography (Box 1)
  - Larue, Gerald A. Euthanasia and Religion (Box 1)
  - Morgan, Ernest. Dealing Creatively With Death. 11th edition. (Box 1)
  - Morgan, Ernest. Dealing Creatively With Death. 12th edition (Box 1)
  - Risley, Robert L. A New Law Permitting Physician Aid-in-Dying (Box 1)
  - Rollin, Betty. Last Wish (Box 1)
  - Smith, David Randolph. Legal Recognition of Neocortical Death (Box 1)
  - Wickett, Ann. Double Exit: When Aging Couples Commit Suicide (Box 1)
  - The Euthanasia Review, Volume 1, Number 1, (Spring 1986) (Box 1)
  - The Euthanasia Review, Volume 1, Number 2, (Summer 1986) (Box 1)
  - The Euthanasia Review, Volume 1, Number 3, (Fall 1986) (Box 1)
  - The Euthanasia Review. Volume 1, Number 4, (Winter 1986) (Box 1)
  - The Euthanasia Review. Volume 2, Number 1, (Spring 1987) (Box 1)
  - The Euthanasia Review. Volume 2, Number 2, (Summer 1987) (Box 1)
  - Hemlock of Tennessee Newsletter - volume 2, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hemlock of Tennessee Newsletter - volume 3, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hemlock of Tennessee Newsletter - volume 4, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hemlock of Tennessee Newsletter - volume 5, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Hemlock of Tennessee Newsletter - volume 6, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Hemlock of Tennessee Newsletter - volume 7, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Hemlock of Tennessee Newsletter - volume 8-10, 1993-95 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hemlock Quarterly National Newsletter, 1983-89 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hemlock Quarterly National Newsletter, 1990-91 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Hemlock Quarterly National Newsletter, 1992-93 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Hemlock Quarterly National Newsletter (Time Lines), 1994-95 (Box 2, Folder 10b)
  - Chapter Leaders’ Newsletters (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Other Local Hemlock Chapter Newsletters, A-K (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Other Local Hemlock Chapter Newsletters, L-N (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Other Local Hemlock Chapter Newsletters, O-Z (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Related Organizations (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Articles and Clippings, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Articles and Clippings, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Articles and Clippings, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Articles and Clippings, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Articles and Clippings, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Articles and Clippings, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Articles and Clippings, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Articles and Clippings, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Articles and Clippings - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Publicity (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Conferences (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1987 - 92 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1993 - 95 (Box 3, Folder 3b)
  - Clinical Ethics Guild (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Legal Information — (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Internal Affairs (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Private (Box 3, Folder 8-10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Survey of California Physicians Regarding Voluntary Active Euthanasia, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cases of Euthanasia, Mercy Killing, Suicide, and Assisted Suicide (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Roper Poll of the West Coast, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5-14)
  - Oregon Death With Dignity Act (Box 3, Folder 5-15)
  - Americans Against Human Suffering (AAHS) (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Hemlock Society of Tennessee Spring 2001 Accession
  - NASA –Investigators Working Group (Box 1)
  - Book-Deadly Compassion: The Death of Ann Humphry and the Truth About Euthanasia by Rita Marker (Box 1)
  - Book- But What If She Wants To Die?: A Husband’s Diary by George E. Delury (Box 1)
  - Book- The Dying Time: Practical Wisdom for the Dying and Their Caregivers by Joan Furman and David McNabb (Box 1)
  - Book-When Is It Right To Die?: Suicide, Euthanasia Suffering Mercy by Joni Eareckson Tada (Box 1)
  - VHS- Dr. Kevorkian on Larry King Live 5/23/95 and Swan Lake 5/5/99 NYC Ballet- The 50th Anniversary (Box 1)
  - VHS- Euthanasia: Murder or Mercy? (#252) (Box 1)
  - VHS- Janet Good and Kevorkian 10/13/96 (Box 1)
  - VHS- 4/24/97 The Plus Side of Nash Maydean Eberling and Dr. Fay Girsh (Hemlock U.S.A. Executive Director) 30 Min. Interview (Box 1)
  - VHS- PBS Channel 8 Broadcast Monday 7/1/96 “Whose Death Is It Anyway?” (Box 1)
  - VHS- Derek Humphey Introducing the Hemlock Society (Box 1)
  - VHS- Mornings on 5; Jesse Van Volkenburg and John Flexnor With May Dean Eberling Air 7/8/90 (Box 1)
  - VHS- Maine Clips 9/30/99 Darlene (WCSH) (Box 1)
  - VHS- 11/24/98 PBS News midtape: Mike Wallace and Dr. Jack Kervorkian and a Discussion on Oregon’s law on assisted death (Box 1)
  - VHS- Golden Opportunities, WKYC, Cleveland, Ohio The Right to Choose to Die 5/2/99 Wynell Schweitzxer-Derek Humphry (Box 1)
  - VHS- The Fight to Die- CNN 8/13/95 (Box 1)
  - VHS- PBS Discusses Final Exit (Box 1)
  - VHS- Mainers for Death with Dignity (Box 1)
  - Hemlock Society U.S.A.- Chapter Leaders’ Resource (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hemlock Society U.S.A.- Timelines Newsletter Jan 1994- Dec 1996 Incomplete (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hemlock Society U.S.A.- Timelines Newsletter Jan 1997- Winter 2001 Incomplete (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hemlock Society U.S.A.- Misc. Materials (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hemlock Society U.S.A.- Misc. Materials (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Monthly mailings from Hemlock Society U.S.A. Jul 1998- Jan 2001 Incomplete- envelopes include member lists and mailing lists among other items (Box 1)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Bank Statements (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Board of Directors (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Bylaws (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Clippings (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Clippings (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Internal Revenue Service (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Living Will and Other Documents (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee-Membership Lists (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Misc. Materials (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Misc. Materials (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Newsletter Jan 1991- Nov 1994 Incomplete (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Newsletter Feb 1995- May 1998 Incomplete (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Postal Information (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- State of Tennessee, including Sales Tax Exemption (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hemlock Society of Tennessee- Vanderbilt University Archival Agreement (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hemlock Societies and Related Organizations from Around the U.S.—Newsletters and Misc. Materials (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hemlock Societies and Related Organizations from Around the U.S.—Newsletters and Misc. Materials (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hemlock Societies and Related Organizations from Around the World—Newsletters and Misc. Materials (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - World Conference on Assisted Dying (Box 2, Folder 22)